<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<books>
    <book isbn-13="9780192804778" isbn-10="0192804774">
        <title>Anarchism: A Very Short Introduction</title>
        <author>Ward, Colin</author>
        <classification>
            <class>anarchism</class>
            <class>philosophy</class>
            <class>ethics</class>
            <class>politics</class>
            <class>social theory</class>
            <class>libertarianism</class>
        </classification>
        <price currency="GBP">
            <rrp>7.99</rrp>
            <price>5.99</price>
        </price>
        <stock>8</stock>
        <format>Paperback</format>
        <pages>128</pages>
        <publisher>OUP Oxford</publisher>
        <publish_date>2004-10-21</publish_date>
        <description> Ward considers anarchism from a variety of perspectives: theoretical,
            historical, and international. The text also explores the ideas of key anarchist
            thinkers from Kropotkin to Chomsky. </description>
    </book>
    <book isbn-13=" 9781851687176" isbn-10="1851687173">
        <title>Anarchism: A Beginner's Guide</title>
        <author>Kinna, Ruth</author>
        <classification>
            <class>anarchism</class>
            <class>philosophy</class>
            <class>ethics</class>
            <class>politics</class>
            <class>social theory</class>
            <class>libertarianism</class>
        </classification>
        <price currency="GBP">
            <rrp>9.99</rrp>
            <price>7.43</price>
        </price>
        <stock>7</stock>
        <format>Paperback</format>
        <pages>192</pages>
        <publisher>Oneworld Publications</publisher>
        <publish_date>2009-09-01</publish_date>
        <description> &quot;A valuable contribution to our understanding of this much
            misunderstood philosophy.&quot; - Howard Zinn, author of A People's History of the
            United States &quot;Ruth Kinna cannot be praised highly enough for writing a
            comprehensive, original and sympathetic work which will no doubt come to be viewed as
            the key text on the subject.&quot; - Simon Tormey, Professor of Politics, University
            of Nottingham </description>
    </book>
    <book isbn-13="9780142437858" isbn-10="0142437859">
        <title>Living My Life</title>
        <author>Goldman, Emma</author>
        <classification>
            <class>biography</class>
            <class>autobiography</class>
            <class>anarchism</class>
            <class>politics</class>
            <class>libertarianism</class>
        </classification>
        <price currency="GBP">
            <rrp>12.99</rrp>
            <price>11.69</price>
        </price>
        <stock>6</stock>
        <format>Paperback</format>
        <pages>448</pages>
        <publisher>Penguin</publisher>
        <publish_date>2006-09-28</publish_date>
        <description> Emma Goldman (1869-1940) came to America from Russia when she was sixteen. As
            a life-long political activist, Goldman's account of her life in agitation for her ideal
            is interesting for the tales of intolerance and brutality practised by the state.
        </description>
    </book>
    <book isbn-13="9781596052819" isbn-10="1596052813">
        <title>Anarchism and Other Essays</title>
        <author>Goldman, Emma</author>
        <classification>
            <class>anarchism</class>
            <class>politics</class>
            <class>feminism</class>
            <class>social justice</class>
        </classification>
        <price currency="GBP">
            <rrp>4.37</rrp>
            <price>4.30</price>
        </price>
        <stock>5</stock>
        <format>Paperback</format>
        <pages>284</pages>
        <publisher>Cosimo Classics</publisher>
        <publish_date>2006-01-31</publish_date>
        <description> Destruction and violence! How is the ordinary man to know that the most
            violent element in society is ignorance; that it's power of destruction is the very
            thing Anarchism is combating? - Emma Goldman, from "Anarchism: What It Really Stands
            For" From the turn of the 20th century to the turn of the 21st, the fiery words of
            "notorious" anarchist Emma Goldman continue to echo with passion, insight, and
            intelligence. Beyond the title essay, Goldman's impassioned calls for equality,
            individual freedom, and social justice encompass: Minorities versus Majorities. The
            Psychology of Political Violence. Prisons: A Social Crime and Failure . Patriotism: A
            Menace to Liberty . The Hypocrisy of Puritanism. The Traffic in Women. The Tragedy of
            Women's Emancipation . Marriage and Love. The Drama: A Powerful Disseminator of Radical
            Thought. and more. They were prophetic when they were first published in 1910, but these
            essays demonstrate that even today Goldman, a thinker of profound wisdom, has not yet
            seen her time come. </description>
    </book>
    <book isbn-13="9781849351034" isbn-10="1849351031">
        <title>Quiet Rumours: An Anarcha-Feminist Reader </title>
        <author>Goldman, Emma</author>
        <author>De Cleyre, Voltairine</author>
        <author>Freeman, Jo</author>
        <author>Kornegger,Peggy</author>
        <author>Levine, Cathy</author>
        <author>Dunbar-Ortiz, Roxanne</author>
        <author>Creando, Mujeres</author>
        <author>Zora, Rote</author>
        <classification>
            <class>anarchism</class>
            <class>politics</class>
            <class>feminism</class>
            <class>social justice</class>
            <class>anthropology</class>
            <class>anthology</class>
        </classification>
        <price currency="GBP">
            <rrp>14.00</rrp>
            <price>12.60</price>
        </price>
        <stock>4</stock>
        <format>Paperback</format>
        <pages>160</pages>
        <publisher>AK Press</publisher>
        <publish_date>2012-10-14</publish_date>
        <description> &quot;Quiet Rumours: An Anarcha-Feminist Reader" is one of my very
            favorite books and I'm thrilled that AK Press just released this expanded third edition.
            This amazing anthology of essays by revolutionary class war feminists includes twenty
            essays and interviews by legendary anarcha-feminists like Emma Goldman, Voltairine de
            Cleyre, and Charlotte Wilson, as well as more contemporary voices. It even includes an
            introduction by Roxanne Dunbar-Ortiz. An internationalist anthology, it includes
            writings by anarchist women from Bolivia, Germany, Ireland, England, and the United
            States. Among the many awesome essays is Jo Freeman's important essay, "The Tyranny of
            Structurelessness" and Cathy Levine's reply, "The Tyranny of Tyranny.&quot; Simply
            put, this book is an anarchist-feminist classic and required reading for every activist
            working to dismantle the patriarchy and global capitalism! </description>
    </book>
    <book isbn="9781904859208" isbn-10="1904859208">
        <title>Chomsky on Anarchism</title>
        <author>Chomsky, Noam</author>
        <classification>
            <class>anarchism</class>
            <class>philosophy</class>
            <class>ethics</class>
            <class>politics</class>
            <class>social theory</class>
            <class>libertarianism</class>
        </classification>
        <price currency="GBP">
            <rrp>11.00</rrp>
            <price>9.90</price>
        </price>
        <stock>8</stock>
        <format>Paperback</format>
        <pages>256</pages>
        <publisher>AK Press</publisher>
        <publish_date>2006-04-02</publish_date>
        <desciption> Chomsky describes the anarchist principles that have guided him since he was a
            teenager. This collection of essays, talks and interviews includes pieces that have
            never been published before, interviews available in English for the first time as well
            as rare, hard to find material. </desciption>
    </book>
    <book isbn="9780486419558" isbn-10="048641955X">
        <title>Anarchism: A Collection of Revolutionary Writings</title>
        <author>Kropotkin, Peter</author>
        <classification>
            <class>anarchism</class>
            <class>philosophy</class>
            <class>ethics</class>
            <class>politics</class>
            <class>social theory</class>
            <class>libertarianism</class>
        </classification>
        <price currency="GBP">
            <rrp>12.49</rrp>
            <price>11.19</price>
        </price>
        <stock>7</stock>
        <format>Paperback</format>
        <pages>336</pages>
        <publisher>Dover Publications</publisher>
        <publish_date>2003-03-28</publish_date>
        <desciption> Peter Kropotkin (1842-1921) was born a prince, but renounced the title at the
            age of twelve, to live a poor life, often persecuted and imprisoned while the Czarist
            regime operated, but always writing, as a scientist, as a traveller in England and in
            Switzerland, and of course, as an expounder of anarchism. </desciption>
    </book>
    <book isbn="9780486224831" isbn-10="048622483X">
        <title>God and the State</title>
        <author>Bakunin, Mikhail</author>
        <classification>
            <class>anarchism</class>
            <class>philosophy</class>
            <class>ethics</class>
            <class>politics</class>
            <class>social theory</class>
            <class>libertarianism</class>
            <class>religion</class>
            <class>atheism</class>
        </classification>
        <price currency="GBP">
            <rrp>8.99</rrp>
            <price>7.19</price>
        </price>
        <stock>6</stock>
        <format>Paperback</format>
        <pages>89</pages>
        <publisher>Dover Publications</publisher>
        <publish_date>2003-03-28</publish_date>
        <desciption> Mikhail Bakunin (1814-1876) is remembered as one of the originators of modern
            anarchy, a foe to Marx, and a radicalizer of youth through Russia and Europe in the 19th
            century. Unfinished at the time of his death and rambling and disjointed at best, this
            book is nevertheless a provocative exploration of Bakunin's ideas on the enslavement of
            humanity by religion, its use by the state as a weapon against the people, and the
            necessity of throwing off the chains of God-worship. </desciption>
    </book>
    <book isbn="9780006862451" isbn-10="0006862454">
        <title>Demanding the Impossible: A History of Anarchism</title>
        <author>Marshall, Peter</author>
        <classification>
            <class>anarchism</class>
            <class>philosophy</class>
            <class>ethics</class>
            <class>politics</class>
            <class>social theory</class>
            <class>libertarianism</class>
            <class>religion</class>
            <class>atheism</class>
        </classification>
        <price currency="GBP">
            <rrp>14.99</rrp>
            <price>11.99</price>
        </price>
        <stock>5</stock>
        <format>Paperback</format>
        <pages>784</pages>
        <publisher>Harper Perennial</publisher>
        <publish_date>2007-11-19</publish_date>
        <desciption> A fascinating and comprehensive history, 'Demanding the Impossible' is a
            challenging and thought-provoking exploration of anarchist ideas and actions from
            ancient times to the present day. Navigating the broad 'river of anarchy', from Taoism
            to Situationism, from Ranters to Punk rockers, from individualists to communists, from
            anarcho-syndicalists to anarcha-feminists, 'Demanding the Impossible' is an
            authoritative and lively study of a widely misunderstood subject. It explores the key
            anarchist concepts of society and the state, freedom and equality, authority and power
            and investigates the successes and failure of the anarchist movements throughout the
            world. While remaining sympathetic to anarchism, it presents a balanced and critical
            account. It covers not only the classic anarchist thinkers, such as Godwin, Proudhon,
            Bakunin, Kropotkin, Reclus and Emma Goldman, but also other libertarian figures, such as
            Nietzsche, Camus, Gandhi, Foucault and Chomsky. No other book on anarchism covers so
            much so incisively. In this updated edition, a new epilogue examines the most recent
            developments, including 'post-anarchism' and 'anarcho-primitivism' as well as the
            anarchist contribution to the peace, green and 'Global Justice' movements. Demanding the
            Impossible is essential reading for anyone wishing to understand what anarchists stand
            for and what they have achieved. It will also appeal to those who want to discover how
            anarchism offers an inspiring and original body of ideas and practices which is more
            relevant than ever in the twenty-first century. </desciption>
    </book>
    <book isbn="9781904859253" isbn-10="1904859259">
        <title>No Gods, No Masters: An Anthology of Anarchism</title>
        <author>Guerin, Daniel (Editor)</author>
        <classification>
            <class>anarchism</class>
            <class>philosophy</class>
            <class>ethics</class>
            <class>politics</class>
            <class>social theory</class>
            <class>libertarianism</class>
            <class>religion</class>
            <class>atheism</class>
            <class>anthology</class>
        </classification>
        <price currency="GBP">
            <rrp>16.95</rrp>
            <price>16.95</price>
        </price>
        <stock>4</stock>
        <format>Paperback</format>
        <pages>500</pages>
        <publisher>AK Press</publisher>
        <publish_date>2006-07-02</publish_date>
        <desciption>Guerin's classic anthology of anarchism translated and reprinted, available for
            the first time in a single volume. It brings together a vast array of unpublished
            documents, letters, debates, manifestos reports, impassioned calls-to-arms and reasoned
            analysis; the history, organisation and practice of the movement - its theorists,
            advocates and activists; the great names and the obscure, towering legends and unsung
            heroes. This definitive collection portrays anarchism as a sophisticated ideology whose
            nuances and complexities highlight the natural desire for freedom in us all.
        </desciption>
    </book>
</books>
